Guide to the Andover Theological Seminary Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Alumni, Series IV
  - Class material
    - Class of 1858: general material (Box 98, Folder 23, 28-29)
    - Class of 1859: biographical sketches, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Class of 1859: [items removed from #100.3], n.d. (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Class of 1859: general material, 1862–1879 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - Class of 1859: photograph album (Box 116)
    - Class of 1860: photograph album (Box 117)
    - Class of 1862: general material, 1894 (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - Class of 1866: general material, 1891 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - Class of 1868: general material, 1833, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - Class of 1868: papers of Wood, William C. (2 volumes), 1868–1869 (Box 157)
    - Class of 1875: general material, 1895–1900 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Class of 1880: general material, 1900–1920 (Box 102, Folder 1-11)
    - Classes, 1881-1882: general material, 1893 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Class of 1888: general material, 1914 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - Class of 1892: general material, 1893 (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Class of 1894: general material, 1896–1899 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Class of 1894: photograph album, Daniel McIntyre (Box 116)
    - Class of 1899: Autobiography, Joseph E. Foster (Box 116)
    - Class of 1899: general material (Box 102, Folder 20)
    - Class of 1899: letters, general, 1899–1953 (Box 102, Folder 16-19)
    - Class of 1899: letters, Andrews – Stevens, 1899–1951 (Box 103, Folder 1-28)
    - Class of 1899: letters, Stevens – Stoneman, 1899–1951 (Box 104, Folder 1-5)
    - Class of 1953: correspondence, 1952–1960 (Box 104, Folder 6-14)
    - Class of 1953:, 1988-2002, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Class of 1953: 40th reunion material, 1993 (Box 104, Folder 16-17)
    - Class of 1953: 45th reunion material, 1998 (Box 104, Folder 18-19)
    - Class of 1953: 50th reunion material, 2003 (Box 104, Folder 20-22)
- Financial, Series V
  - Account books: cash books
    - Cash books, 1808–1843 (Box 60)
    - Cash books (volumes 1-5), 1908–1947 (Box 60–61)
  - Account books: donors and funds
    - General funds: ledger, 1885–1908 (Box 59)
    - General funds: [#1-2] (Box 20)
    - Lieutenant Governor Samuel Phillips Fund: account book, 1834–1840 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Lieutenant Governor Samuel Phillips Fund: ledger, #1, 1802–1887 (Box 55)
    - Lieutenant Governor Samuel Phillips Fund: ledger, #2, 1802–1804 (Box 31)
    - Lieutenant Governor Samuel Phillips Fund: order book, 1906–1907 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Log book re: donors and benefactors of the theological institution, 1808–1831 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Log book re: New England beneficiaries of the theological institution, 1808–1818 (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Medway Fund: account book, 1822–1833 (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Account books: general accounts
    - Account books, 1810–1842 (Box 85, Folder 1-8)
    - Account books, 1835–1837 (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Ledgers, 1808–1848 (Box 23)
    - Ledgers, 1808–1885 (Box 58)
    - Ledgers, 1809–1841 (Box 24)
    - Ledgers, 1809–1908 (Box 58)
    - Ledgers, 1811–1845 (Box 25)
    - Ledgers, 1817–1845 (Box 50)
    - Ledgers, 1831–1841 (Box 26)
    - Ledgers, 1833–1843 (Box 23)
    - Ledgers, 1837–1840 (Box 84)
    - Ledgers, 1841–1908 (Box 51)
    - Ledgers, 1842–1846 (Box 51)
    - Ledgers, 1842–1857 (Box 50)
    - Ledgers, 1848–1851 (Box 47)
    - Ledgers, 1857–1870 (Box 52)
    - Ledgers, 1870–1880 (Box 52)
    - Ledgers, 1880–1883 (Box 19)
    - Ledgers, 1880–1888 (Box 59)
    - Ledgers, 1883–1889 (Box 19)
    - Ledgers, 1888–1897 (Box 53)
    - Ledgers, 1894–1900 (Box 27)
    - Ledgers, 1897–1908 (Box 53)
    - Ledgers, 1908–1950 (Box 28)
    - Ledgers, 1908–1952 (Box 29)
    - Ledgers, 1908–1948 (Box 54)
    - Ledgers, 1909–1926 (Box 30)
  - Other financial records
    - Account book re: William Bartlet, Esquire, 1817–1841 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Account sheets, 1810–1900 (Box 85, Folder 11-18)
    - Account sheets, 1850-1888, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 1-22)
    - Security registers, 1809–1849 (Box 89, Folder 4-5)
    - Funds and Statutes report, 1909 (Box 91)
    - Funds and Statutes report, 1839–1840 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Funds and Statutes report, 1850–1878 (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Funds and Statutes report [#1-2], 1907–1908 (Box 90, Folder 6-7)
    - Funds and Statutes report [#1] (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Funds and Statutes report [#2-4] (Box 89, Folder 1-3)
    - Subscription books, 1846–1876 (Box 90, Folder 1-4)
    - Treasurer's reports: bound, 1909–1947 (Box 91–92)
    - Treasurer's reports: pamphlets, 1867–1940 (Box 93)
- Legal, Series VI
  - Court cases
    - Andover Theological Seminary vs. Attorney General:
      - Bill of Complaint, 1928 (Box 128, Folder 1-2)
      - final decree, 1931 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Andover Theological Seminary vs. Attorney General and Phillips Academy:
      - final decree, 1931 (Box 128, Folder 4-6)
    - Andover Theological Seminary vs. Phillips Academy:
      - addenda, 1923 (Box 128, Folder 7)
      - appeal, 1923 (Box 128, Folder 8)
      - brief, 1925 (Box 128, Folder 9-10)
      - decree, 1925 (Box 128, Folder 11)
      - opinion, 1925 (Box 128, Folder 12)
      - petition, 1926 (Box 128, Folder 13)
      - reservation, 1924 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Kimball, John vs. New Hampshire Bible Society:
      - additional brief (Trustees), 1888 (Box 128, Folder 15)
      - brief (heirs of W. Richardson), 1888 (Box 128, Folder 16)
      - brief (Trustees), 1888 (Box 128, Folder 17)
      - brief (Trustees), n.d. (Box 128, Folder 18)
      - opinion, 1887 (Box 128, Folder 19)
    - Mitchison, Richard Edmund:
      - appendices, A-L, 1887 (Box 106, Folder 10)
      - opinion, manuscript, 1887 (Box 106, Folder 9)
      - opinion, official, 1887 (Box 106, Folder 3)
      - opinion, translation, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2)
      - precedents, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Other cases:
      - Harvard University vs. Board of Assessors of statement Cambridge, 1899 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - Hinkley vs. Thatcher, brief, 1885 (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - Lieutenant-Governor Phillips funds, 1902 (Box 129, Folder 3)
      - Murdock, James, documents, 1821-1829, n.d. (Box 144, Folder 6-7)
      - Nelson vs. Cushing, lawsuit, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - Nicholas Pike Donation, opinion, 1912 (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - Smith, Jeremiah, opinion, 1807 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Phillips Academy vs. Andover Theological Seminary
      - brief, 1925 (Box 129, Folder 7)
      - decree, 1925 (Box 129, Folder 8)
      - reservation, 1924 (Box 129, Folder 9-10)
    - Ryder, W.H
      - answers to questions, 1895 (Box 129, Folder 11)
      - documents, 1895 (Box 129, Folder 12-14)
      - letter re: case, 1895 (Box 129, Folder 15)
      - letters and documents, 1896 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - Smyth, Egbert C.:
      - amendment, 1892 (Box 129, Folder 17)
      - Andover Case (bound) (Box 131)
      - appeals, 1889–1890 (Box 129, Folder 18-19)
      - appointment, 1882 (Box 129, Folder 23)
      - argument, 1886 (Box 129, Folder 20)
      - arguments, appellant, 1890 (Box 129, Folder 21)
      - arguments, Trustees, 1890 (Box 129, Folder 22)
      - arguments, Visitors, 1887 (Box 180)
      - Bill of Complaint, 1886 (Box 130, Folder 1-2)
      - brief, appellant, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 3-4)
      - brief, additional causes, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - brief, appeal, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - brief, final hearing, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - brief, Trustees, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 8-9)
      - brief, Visitors, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 11-12)
      - brief, Visitors: preliminary report, 1888 (Box 130, Folder 13)
      - clipping, 1891 (Box 130, Folder 14)
      - court order, 1891 (Box 130, Folder 15)
      - decision, 1888 (Box 130, Folder 16)
      - decree, 1892 (Box 130, Folder 17)
      - docket, 1890 (Box 130, Folder 18)
      - judgement, 1887 (Box 130, Folder 19)
      - letters, 1888–1893 (Box 130, Folder 20-24)
      - memorandum, 1892 (Box 134, Folder 1)
      - opinion, 1887 (Box 134, Folder 2)
      - opinion: evidence of prejudice, 1887 (Box 134, Folder 3)
      - petition, 1887 (Box 134, Folder 4)
      - preamble, 1892 (Box 134, Folder 5)
      - publication, Andover Heresy, 1887 (Box 134, Folder 6)
      - publication, Andover Trial, 1887 (Box 134, Folder 7)
      - report, 1892 (Box 134, Folder 8)
      - report: litigation, 1892 (Box 134, Folder 9)
      - report: Master's report [copies #1-2], 1922 (Box 134, Folder 10-11)
      - response, 1888 (Box 134, Folder 12)
      - statements, 1887–1888 (Box 134, Folder 13-15)
      - transcript, 1889 (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - Incorporation records
    - Associate Statutes: original, 1808 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Associate Statutes: [photocopy, 1808 statutes], n.d. (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - By-laws: Smith Professorship, 1867 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Constitution and Associate Statutes: bound, 1808 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Constitution and Statutes, 1839 (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Documents re: Brown Professorship, 1812-1847, n.d. (Box 144, Folder 8-10)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1811 (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1817 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1827 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1837 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1846 (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1857 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1870 (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Laws re: the theological institution, 1894 (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Laws re: Chapter V revisions, 1866 (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Incorporation records [photocopies, 1870 documents], n.d. (Box 105, Folder 16)
  - Merger: Harvard University
    - Appeal, 1922 (Box 134, Folder 17)
    - Argument, 1908 (Box 134, Folder 18)
    - Bill of Complaint [copies #1-2], 1922 (Box 134, Folder 19-20)
    - typescript, 1922 (Box 134, Folder 21-22)
    - Brief, 1907 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Brief re: relocation, 1907 (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Clippings: unsorted, n.d. (Box 136)
    - Clippings: W.R. Campbell files, 1920–1926 (Box 135, Folder 3-5)
    - Correspondence: Board of Trustees, 1922–1930 (Box 135, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Board of Visitors, 1922–1931 (Box 135, Folder 6-15)
    - Documents re: Cambridge move, 1906 (Box 135, Folder 16-17)
    - Documents re. planned affiliation, n.d. (Box 135, Folder 18)
    - Evidence (volumes 1-2), 1922 (Box 132)
    - Hearing (parts 1-2), 1908 (Box 135, Folder 19-20)
    - Hearing: closer affiliation, 1922 (Box 133)
    - Memorandum, 1908 (Box 135, Folder 21)
    - Opinion, 1908 (Box 135, Folder 22)
    - Papers, 1922–1926 (Box 135, Folder 23-25)
    - Proceedings (bound), 1908 (Box 131)
    - Reasons re: establishment, 1908 (Box 135, Folder 26)
  - Property records
    - Index re: Acts of General Court of theological seminary (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - records of theological seminary, 1807–1841 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Official records, 1827–1828 (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Property deed, 1912 (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Report re: real estate of Phillips Academy, 1903 (Box 106, Folder 6)
- Library, Series VII
  - Administrative records
    - Accession log, 1819–1826 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Account book, 1866-1905, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1910, 1926 (Box 84, Folder 1-6)
    - Drawings re: Brechen Hall Library, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Other papers, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Notes re: history of library, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Portraits, 1911 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Pamphlets re: library rules, 1831 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Supplemental purchases, 1897–1901 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Phillips Fund Books: published lists, 1908–1910 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Publications: Decimal Systems for Libraries, 1856 (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Unsorted material, n.d. (Box 181)
  - Circulation records
    - Ledgers, 1808–1831 (Box 49)
    - Ledgers, 1810 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Ledgers, 1812–1841 (Box 49)
    - Ledgers, 1819 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Ledgers, 1831–1840 (Box 76, Folder 2-8)
    - Ledgers, 1834–1836 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Ledgers, 1840–1841 (Box 32)
    - Ledgers: [#1-2], 1841 (Box 56)
    - Ledgers, 1841–1842 (Box 57)
    - Ledgers, 1842–1843 (Box 54)
    - Ledgers, 1843 (Box 56)
    - Ledgers, 1845 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1846 (Box 48)
    - Ledgers, 1846–1847 (Box 33)
    - Ledgers, 1846–1848 (Box 48)
    - Ledgers, 1846–1849 (Box 33)
    - Ledgers, 1847 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1848–1849 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1850–1851 (Box 57)
    - Ledgers, 1851–1852 (Box 57)
    - Ledgers, 1852–1853 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1853–1858 (Box 76, Folder 9-12)
    - Ledgers, 1854–1855 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Ledgers, 1858–1859 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Ledgers, 1858–1864 (Box 77, Folder 1-6)
    - Ledgers, 1866–1905 (Box 77, Folder 7-12)
    - Ledgers, 1868–1872 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1872–1876 (Box 63)
    - Ledgers, 1876–1880 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers, 1878–1882 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers, 1883–1886 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers, 1886–1895 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers, 1892–1897 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers, 1897–1905 (Box 62)
    - Ledgers: [#1], n.d. (Box 32)
    - Ledgers: [#2-3], n.d. (Box 56)
    - Ledgers: [#4], n.d. (Box 80)
    - Log books, 1810 (Box 87, Folder 1-12)
  - Inventory catalogs: internal
    - Catalogs, 1826–1836 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Catalogs, 1932–1955 (Box 79, Folder 2-3)
    - Catalogs [#1-2], n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Catalogs [#3], n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Catalogs [#4], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 12-14)
    - Catalogs: donation: anonymous donation, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Catalogs: donation: Stuart donation, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Catalogs: supplement, 1809 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Catalogs: supplement, 1838 (Box 88, Folder 10-16)
    - Catalogs: supplement, 1849 (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - Inventory catalogs: published
    - Catalogs: bound, 1819 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Catalogs: general, 1838 (Box 82)
    - Catalogs: manuscript, 1838 (Box 83)
    - Catalogs: [notations], 1838 (Box 81, Folder 2-7)
    - Catalogs: supplement, 1838 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Catalogs: supplement, 1849 (Box 82)
    - Catalogs: unbound, 1819 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Andover-Harvard Theological Library
    - Agreement: legal document, 1910 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - pamphlet, 1923 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1937–1945 (Box 181)
    - Catalog: published, 1918 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Catalog: published, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Inventory catalog re:
    - Andover holdings at Harvard (internal) (Box 88, Folder 6-8)
    - Chinese Department (internal), 1877 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Related material, n.d. (Box 181)
- History, Series VIII
  - 100th anniversary material
    - Addresses, centennial, 1908 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Addresses, centennial (bound), 1908 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - Commemorative book, 1908 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: acceptance and regrets, 1908 (Box 117, Folder 2-11)
    - Correspondence re: class reunions, 1908 (Box 117, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence re: congratulations, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence re: institutional representation, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: program events, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: regrets, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 5-10)
    - Invitations and programs, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - Lists: guest, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Lists: invitation, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 12-13)
    - Notes re: school history, 1908 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Other records
    - 125th anniversary, 1933 (Box 139, Folder 15-16)
    - 150th anniversary: correspondence, news releases, and programs, 1958 (Box 139, Folder 18-19)
    - 150th anniversary: proclamation, Harvard University, 1958 (Box MC3, Folder 12)
    - 150th anniversary: program, 1958 (Box MC3, Folder 14)
    - 200th anniversary: Jonathan Edwards Society, correspondence, 1903 (Box 180)
    - Anniversary Programs, Inaugurations, Etc. (bound), 1935–1955 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Campus activities: programs, fliers, etc., 1861–1953 (Box 154, Folder 55-58)
    - Campus activities: programs, fliers, etc. (Box 154, Folder 8-13)
    - Catalog sheet: members of ATS, 1873 (Box MC3, Folder 1)
    - Certificates (samples), 1827 (Box MC3, Folder 3)
    - Certificates (samples), 1862, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 1-3)
    - Charter: Phillips Academy, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 13)
    - Clippings [photocopies, 1859-1900, n.d.] (Box 142)
    - Correspondence: other (Box 144, Folder 16)
    - Diploma: Marshall, Albert (Class of 1872) (rolled), n.d. (Box MC3)
    - Diploma: McNair (rolled), n.d. (Box MC3)
    - Diploma: Miller, Simeon (rolled) STB, 20th century (blank) (rolled), n.d. n.d. (Box MC1)
    - Diploma: STB, 20th century (blank) (rolled), n.d. n.d. (Box MC1)
    - Funeral address (Ahmadorgan, India): Hume, Robert (Box MC3, Folder 7-8)
    - Guest register, 1856–1866 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Guest register, 1858 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Guest register, 1902–1907 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Informational brochures, pamphlets, etc., 1900-1922, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 14-15)
    - Map: Andover, Massachusetts, 1836 (Box MC3, Folder 10)
    - Map: location of ATS students in U.S., 1920 (Box MC3, Folder 4)
    - New building: general material, 1910–1917 (Box 144, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper: Andover Townsman (supplement), issue re: Phillips Academy bicentennial, 1978 (Box MC3, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers: The Democrat, article re: opening of ATS, 1808 (Box MC3, Folder 9)
    - Other papers, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 17)
    - Poem: Andover Mill or Minister's Factory (Box MC3, Folder 11)
    - Poster: auction, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 4)
    - Poster: Battle of Plaitsburgh, 1895 (Box MC3, Folder 6)
    - Poster: Churchill lecture, 1880 (Box MC3, Folder 5)
    - Poster: Oriental poster, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 8)
    - Registrar sheet: student record (blank), 1908 (Box MC3, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbooks [#1-4], n.d. (Box 176)
    - Text: Japanese characters, 1874 (Box MC3, Folder 11)
- Images, Series IX
  - Other material
    - Ambrotype: Goodell, William, 1820 (Box 177)
    - Cartoon: political, 1886 (Box MC3, Folder 4)
    - Drawing: Rogers, William M. (Class of 1830), n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 28)
    - Glass plate negatives: campus, general view, n.d. (Box 177)
    - Glass plate negatives: Judson, Adoniram, 1810 (Box 177)
    - Lithographs: Andover campus (Box MC2, Folder 16)
    - Photograph albums, n.d. (Box 174)
  - Photographs: campus, events, and related organizations
    - Campus:
      - 19th century (early), n.d. (Box 175, Folder 1)
      - 19th century (late), n.d. (Box 175, Folder 2)
      - general, 1830–1840 (Box MC2, Folder 4)
      - general, 1877 (Box 175, Folder 39)
      - general, 1908 (Box MC2, Folder 3)
      - general, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 5)
      - Andover chapel, ca.1877 (Box MC3, Folder 15)
      - Andover Hall: [#1] (Box MC2, Folder 1)
      - Andover Hall: [#2] (Box MC2, Folder 7)
      - Andover Hall: Brown Room, fireplace area (Box MC2, Folder 10)
      - Andover Hall: Brown Room, lounge area (Box MC2, Folder 9)
      - Andover Hall: Reading Room (Box MC2, Folder 8)
      - Bartlett Chapel, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 15)
      - Brechin Hall Library, 1863–1902 (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - Brechin Hall Library, 1876 (Box MC2, Folder 2)
      - Campus grounds, 1851 (Box MC2, Folder 19)
      - Hall, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 13)
      - Interiors, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 18)
      - Library: reading room, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 40)
      - Sanctuary, 1911 (Box MC2, Folder 6)
      - Sanctuary, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 12)
      - Shaw House: group photograph, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 16)
      - Stained glass window (Box MC2, Folder 14)
      - Stairs, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 11)
      - Stowe House, 1876, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 4)
      - Tucker Home, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Events:
      - 150th anniversary, 1958 (Box 175, Folder 30)
      - Easter School, 1905 (Box MC1, Folder 10)
    - Related organizations:
      - Abbot Academy, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 7)
      - Female Academy, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: faculty and staff
    - Faculty: early 1900s, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 12-13)
    - groups, 1863–1908 (Box MC1, Folder 25)
    - groups, 1883–1887 (Box MC3, Folder 17)
    - groups, 1883–1899 (Box MC1)
    - groups, 1896 (Box MC2, Folder 17)
    - groups, 1897 (Box 175, Folder 35)
    - groups, 1898 (Box MC1, Folder 21)
    - groups, 1908 (Box MC1, Folder 10)
    - portraits, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 41)
    - Librarian Ropes, 1852 (Box MC2, Folder 17)
    - Professor Park (plaque), n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 16)
    - Professor Stuart, 1909 (Box MC1, Folder 14)
    - Professor Stuart (rolled), n.d. (Box MC1)
    - Unidentified faculty, 1862–1878 (Box 175, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: students
    - Class of 1859, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 9-10)
    - classes, 1862-1864, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 11-14)
    - Class of 1868, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 17)
    - classes, 1868-1870, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 15-18)
    - Class of 1871, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 1)
    - Class of 1873, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 2)
    - Class of 1877 or 1878, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 3)
    - classes, 1878-1882, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 19-23)
    - classes, 1887-1888, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 4)
    - Class of 1888, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 36)
    - Class of 1890, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 24)
    - Class of 1892, n.d (Box MC1, Folder 7)
    - Class of 1893, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 18-19)
    - Class of 1894, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 20)
    - Class of 1895, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 25)
    - Class of 1898, n.d. (Box MC2, Folder 17)
    - Class of 1899: 1910 reunion (Box MC1, Folder 23)
    - classes, 1899-1901, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 26-27)
    - classes, 1912-1914, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 28)
    - classes, 1913-1914, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 27)
    - Class of 1922, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 29)
    - Class: unidentified, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 30)
    - Adoniram Judson, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 44)
    - Group: Andover chapel (Box MC3, Folder 18)
    - Groups, ca.1871-1872 (Box 175, Folder 43)
    - Portraits, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 42)
  - Photographs: unidentified
    - Unidentified, 1880-1889, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 37-38)
    - Unidentified, 1884–1886 (Box 175, Folder 45)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 175, Folder 32-34, 46)
    - Unidentified: group, 1893 (Box MC1, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified: group, 1899 (Box MC1, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified: group, 1904 (Box MC1, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified: group, 1914–1915 (Box MC1, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified: portrait, n.d. (Box MC1, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified: portraits, n.d. (Box MC3, Folder 19)
- Publications, Series X
  - Catalogs (bound)
    - Annual catalogs, 1808–1922 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Annual catalogs (3 volumes), 1810–1895 (Box 179)
    - Annual catalogs, 1908–1922 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Annual catalogs volume 1-5, 1810–1922 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
    - General catalogs, 1808–1908 (Box 66–67)
    - General catalogs, 1808–1908 (Box 179)
    - General catalogs, 1810–1849 (Box 180)
    - General catalogs, 1820–1922 (Box 180)
    - General catalogs, 1822 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - General catalogs, 1880 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - General catalogs: volume 1, 1815–1857 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - General catalogs: volume 2, 1867–1880 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - General catalogs, 1909–1927 (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
    - Theological Seminary Bulletin, 1882–1892 (Box 72)
    - Triennial catalog, 1870 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Catalogs (unbound)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1810–1839 (Box 35, Folder 1-17)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1818 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1839–1860 (Box 36, Folder 1-11)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1860–1876 (Box 37)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1876–1890 (Box 38)
    - Annual/general catalogs, 1880 (Box 44)